American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 19, 1897; 11x8-1/2; University of the United States, National committee...to promote the establishment of
    Washington, A.L.S.: John W[esley] Hoyt 1p., end. Asks for Fraley's address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 19, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Zentralblatt für anthropologie
    Stettin, Typed L.S.: Buschau, on postal card 1p., end., and add. In German Cannot exchange.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 20, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 2p. Angry remarks on poor quality of illustrations for his paper on Pennsylvania German illumination. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 424-433.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Nov. 21, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Institut égyptien
    Cairo, A.L.S.: Léon Vidal 2p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 21, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Nansen, Fridtjof, 1861-1930
    Minneapolis, Minn., L.S.: Lionel Clapham, Secretary 1p. Acknowledge receipt of Report.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1897; 10x8; Hewett, Waterman Thomas, 1846-1921
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S.3p. Submits paper on sources of Goethe's printed text.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, Nov. 22, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; John Wanamaker (Firm)
    Phila., L. 1p. and add. Order for books.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 22, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on Hebrew Sabbath. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p. 499.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 22, 1897; Ranck, George Washington, 1841-1900
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 23, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Bullowa, Ferdinand Ezra M.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 23, 1897; 8x8; Prescott, Frank C.
    Redlands, Cal., Typed L.S. with stamp 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Nov. 23, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Vaughan, Alfred Jefferson, 1800-1871
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 24, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; L' Anthropologie
    Paris, A.L. on postal card, S.: M[arcellin] Boule 1p., end., and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 24, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns report of Committee on Revision of the Laws.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 24, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Will meet Sachse.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Nov. 24, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Nelson, William, 1847-1914
    Paterson, N.J., Typed L.S. with MS. correction 1p., end. Inquiry about early New Jersey news papers.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 25, 1897; 10x8; Institution of Civil Engineers (Great Britain)
    [London], Typed L.S.: J. H. T. Tudsbery 1p. Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Nov. 29, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Batchellor, Albert Stillman, 1850-1913
    Littleton, [N.H.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns the edition of New Hampshire State Papers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 29, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Hewett, Waterman Thomas, 1846-1921
    Ithaca, N.Y., A.L.S.1p. Sends paper on sources of Goethe's printed text.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 29, 1897; 11x8-1/2; The Jewish exponent
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Nov. 30, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Dreer, Ferdinand J. (Ferdinand Julius), 1812-1902
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns marginal notes on A.P.S. copy of Declaration of Independence. Refers to Simon Gratz. F.M. Etting, P.S. Plowman, F.D. Stone.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov., 1897; 11x8-1/2; Morgan, C. T.
    Durango, Colo., [,]. A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov., 1897; 10x8-1/2; Literary and Philosophical Society of Liverpool
    Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Rob[er]t F[rederick] Green 1p. Thanks for publications.
  - Concerning the "Symbolic account of the migration of the Aztecs", Dec. 1, 1897; 8x5-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    A.D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to J[ulius] F[riedrich] Sachse, Dec. 1, 1897; 4-1/2x8-1/2; Stockhausen, P.C., co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns plates for H.C. Mercer's paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 2, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    Washington, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks for A.P.S. contribution to his Catalogue of scientific and technical periodicals, 2d ed., 1898.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Dec. 3, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2, 5-1/2x8, 6-3/4x8; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p. 2 encs. Sends abstracts of two papers on Indian languages. Refers to Hays.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 3, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    Washington, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Last call for report to his Catalogue of Scientific Periodicals.
  - Letter to H[enry] Carrington Bolton, Dec. 3, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends checklist of Part I for his Catalogue of Scientific and Technical Periodicals.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 3, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Hucke, Julius
    Berlin, A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Sends copy of his book, Die geldverrichtungen.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 4, 1897; 8x5; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Enc. wanting Returns form and asks for another.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Dec. 4, 1897; 8x5; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge [Mass.] A.L.S. 4p. Concerns location of engraved plate of Declaration of Independence executed by his father, Charles Toppan, in 1829.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 8, 1897; 8x5-1/2; University of Pennsylvania. Library
    Phila., A.L.S.: Morris Jastrow Jr. 1p., end. Concerns missing issues of Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 9, 1897; 13-1/2x8-1/2; Kaiserlich-Königliche Militärgeographisches Institut in Wien
    Vienna, L. 1p., end. Declines to exchange further.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, Dec. 9, 1897; 9x6; Montgomery, Thomas Harrison, 1873-1912
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends list of his scientific writings. Gives biographical information.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 9, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p. Enc. wanting Sends checklist for Bolton's Catalogue of Scientific and Technical Periodicals.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 10, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns T.J.J. See's paper on the evolution of stellar systems. Refers to address of Percival Lowell. For See's paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 19, pp. 221-235.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Dec. 10, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Horn's death. Protests possible election of John Bernhard Smith. Concerns his paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 10, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Loveday, Walter
    Tacoma, Wash., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 10, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Gives qualifications of various Princeton faculty members.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society; Phila.], Dec. 11, [1897]; 7x4-1/2; Harding, George, 1826?-1902
    L. in 3d person 1p., end. Concerns his attendance at meetings.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 12, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Arranges to read paper on the Hebrew Sabbath. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p.499.
  - Letter to [Charles Leander] Doolittle, Dec. 12, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; See, T. J. J. (Thomas Jefferson Jackson), b. 1866
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns illness of Percival Lowell. Written on same sheet is Doolittle to Hays, [1897].
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 13, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Faculté des sciences de Marseille
    Marseille, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: G. Fleury 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 13, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L.S. 2p. Asks for meeting of officers and Council.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 13, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; New York Public Library
    New York, A.L.S.: Wilberforce Eames 2p. Inquires about APS Jefferson draft of Declaration of Independence.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 13, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; University of Kansas
    Lawrence, Kan., L. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 14, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his failure to attend meetings.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Prime, Dec. 14, 1897; 8x5; Gill, Theodore, 1837-1914
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Endorses nomination of W.H. Dall.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1897; 6-3/4x8; Marks, William Dennis, 1849-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his attendance at meetings. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, Dec. 14, 1897; 8X5-1/4; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p., end Concerns her attendance at meetings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1897; 9x5-1/2; Pemberton, Henry, 1826-1911
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1897; 6-3/4x8; Sellers, William, 1824-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his attendance at meetings.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 15, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p., end. with Fraley's opinion Concerns eligibility of various members to vote in annual election.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 15, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Snowden, Archibald Loudon, 1837-1912
    Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his attendance at meetings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 15, 1897; 4-1/2x8-1/2; Stockhausen, P.C., co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns plates for R.H. Mathew's paper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 15, [1897]; 7x4-1/2; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, [Pa.], L.S. 2p. Concerns illustrations for his paper on Pennsylvania German illumination. Refers to Saches. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 424-433.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 16, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to see MSS. of Barcelona Inquisition.
  - Telegram to J. M. Hayes [sic], Dec. 16, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., D. 1p. Concerns illustrations. Refers to J.F. Sachse.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 16, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; New York Public Library
    New York, Typed L.S.: Wilberforce Eames 1p. Thanks for information about Jefferson draft of Declaration of Independence.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 16, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Lakewood, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. end. Concerns his failure to attend meetings.
  - Letter to J[ames] Cheston Morris, Dec. 16, 1897; 8x5; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge [Mass.] A.L.S. 2p. Encs. wanting Concerns Charles Toppan's engraving of plate of Declaration of Independence. Enclosed letter states that he used Washington copy.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 17, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Introduces A.S.W. Rosenbach, who is working on the Rittenhouse orrery.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 17, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends gallery proof of paper on Pennsylvania German illuminations. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 424-433.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 17, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Merrick, John Vaughan, 1828?-1906
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns papers of a samuel Merrick to be examined.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 17, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Randall, Frederick H.
    Denver, Colo., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley], Dec. 18, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Ashley, Frederick William, 1863-1942
    Painesville, 0., Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Dec. 18, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Pennypacker, Samuel W. (Samuel Whitaker), 1843-1916
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Arranges meeting.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Dec. 18, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Free Library of Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: John Thomson 1p., end. Has received unmarked package from London. Is it yours?
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 20, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends for MS. of the Inquisition of Barcelona.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 21, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Garrett, Philip C. (Philip Cresson), 1834-1905
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Nominates Jayne for Treasurer.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 21, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Wolff, Samuel Lee, 1874-1941
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 21, [1897]; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Stürcke, Louis
    New York, A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 22, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. concerns bibliography of Cope.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 22, 1897; 8-1/2x8-1/2; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Has appointed Committee on the Revision of the Laws.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 22, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Platt, Franklin, 1844-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Declines to serve on Committee on Historical Manuscripts.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 22, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sedgwick, Arthur G. (Arthur George), 1844-1915
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize. Refers to J.L. Cadwalader and S.W. Mitchell.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 23, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; W.H. Lowdermilk & Co.
    Washington, Typed L. on postal card 1p. and add. Quotation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 23, 1897; 8x5; Royal Astronomical Society
    London, A.L.S.: W. H. Wesley 2p. Exchange of publications. Refers to H.H. Turner.
  - Letter to [William] Pepper, Dec. 24, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Enc. of 3p. printed prospectus Concerns his paper on the Hebrew Sabbath. Encloses prospectus for lectures by T.K. Cheyne.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 24, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Fraley has appointed committee on W.T. Hewett's paper.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 27, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Enc. wanting Send Phillips circular to A.G. Sedgwick. For enclosure, see Sedgwick to Fraley, Dec. 22, 1897.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 27, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Hastings, W. G. (William Granger), 1853-1937
    Wilber, Neb., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 27, 1897; 8x5; Mallet, John William
    Charlottesville, Va., A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Enc. wanting Sends payment for Proceedings, 1898.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 28, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Butt, Festus O.
    Berryville, Ark., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Nansen, Fridtjof, 1861-1930
    Binghampton, N.Y., L.S.: Lionel Clapham, Secretary 2p. Enc. wanting Sends MS. of remarks made at Nansen meeting.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 28, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. Enc. wanting Concerns checklist for Bolton's Catalogue of Scientific and Technical Periodicals.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 29, 1897; 10x8; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Will read paper on aurora borealis at next meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 37, pp. 4-7.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 29, 1897; 9-3/4x6-1/2; Gill, Theodore, 1837-1914
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Recommends paper by Harriet Richardson on Rocinela. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 8-17.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 30, 1897; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts chairmanship of committee on W.T. Hewett's paper, "The sources of Goethe's printed text: Hermann und Dorothea." Not published by A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2, 7-3/4x5; John Crerar Library
    Chicago, Typed L.S.: C[lement] W. Andrews 1p., end. Enc. of 4p. printed leaflet Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p. Lists his nominations for officers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1897; 6-3/4x4-3/4; Atterbury, Albert H.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 31, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Furness, Horace Howard, 1833-1912
    Wallingford, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Begs to be released from committee on Hewett's paper.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Dec. 31, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Sedgwick, Arthur G. (Arthur George), 1844-1915
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Questions wording of Phillips prize circular.
  - 1897
    - Deposits of the APS natural history collection at the Academy of Natural Sciences, Phila., 1897-1950; American Philosophical Society
    - Receipt for membership certificate, 1897; 4-1/2x7-1/4; American Philosophical Society
      Phila., Printed Ds. S.: Edw[ard] S[ylvester] Morse, Joseph Willcox, [Pierre Eugene] M[arcelin] Bertholot 3 items.
    - Subscription form for Proceedings, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
      Phila., Printed D.S.: J[ohn] W[illiam] Mallet, with MS. addition 1p., end. Refers to J.S. Price.
    - Letter to the American philosophical society, 1897; 8x5; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
      New York, A.L.S. 2p. Refers to his attendance at Nansen meeting,
    - Letter to Frederick Fraley, [1897]; 5-1/2x8; Atkinson, I. S.
      Orange, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
    - Note to [Persifor Frazer?, 1897; 5-3/4x3-1/2; Haehnlen, Marie E.
      Phila., A.N. in 3d person 1p. Report on G.H. Horn's health.
    - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Haehnlen, Marie E.
      [Phila.,]. A.L.S. 1p. Report on G.H. Horn's health.
    - Note to [MacCalla & co.;]., 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
      A.N. 1p. Asks about weight of Proceedings.
    - List of scientific periodicals in A.P.S. Library, [1897]; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
      Phila., D. 1p. Prepared for Bolton's Catalogue of Scientific Periodicals. With copy.
    - Memoranda on exchange of publications with New South Wales Department of Mines and Agriculture, [1897]; 4-1/2x7, 11x8-1/2, 12-1/2x7-3/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
      D. 3 items 3p.
    - Notes on construction of stacks and cabinets, [1897]; 3-3/4x4-1/2 to 10-3/4x7-1/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
      A.D. 10p. varying sizes from
    - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, [1897]; 8x5; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
      Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns publications of Anthropological Society of Washington. Refers to Hodge.
    - Letter to the [American philosophical society], [1897]; 6-1/2x5, 1-1/4x3; Hogan, K. E.
      New York, [1897]. A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. Inquires about Phillips prize listed on enclosed clipping.
    - Letter to the [American philosophical society], 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Leeds Philosophical & Literary Society
      A.L.S.: H.Crowther, Curator 1p. Cannot supply missing parts.
    - Letter to the American philosophical society, 1897; 8-1/2x6-3/4; Lynch, Theodore
      San Francisco, [Cal.,]. A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Inquires about Phillips prize.
    - Memorandum on weight of Proceedings, 1897; 3-1/2x9-1/4; MacCalla & co.
      [Phila.,]. D. 1p., end. by Hays
    - Letter to Harrison Allen, [1897]; 8x5; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
      Parramatta, N.S. Wales, A.L.S. 3p. Concerns his papers on Australian rock carvings and paintings. For papers, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 195-208, 466-478.
    - Letter to the [American philosophical society], 1897; 9X5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
      [Doylestown, Pa., Monday [1897]. A.L.S. 1P. Asks to see revised proof of paper on sloth. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 36-70.]
    - Letter to McCalla & co., 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
      Doylestown, [Pa.], Sunday []. A.L.S. 2p. Concerns illustrations for paper on sloth. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 36-70.
    - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
      [Phila.,]. A.L.S. 1p., end. Orders copies of cushing's paper.
    - Letter to Frederick Fraley, [1897]; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Watson, Archibald R.
      Northport, New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
    - Letter to Fred[erick Fraley, 1897; 8x5; Du Bois, A. Jay (Augustus Jay), 1849-1915
      ]. A.L.S. 1p. Recommends Westlund. Written on verso of letter from A.W. Phillips to DuBois, May 26, 1897.
    - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, [1897]; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
      A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Percival Lowell. Written on same sheet as T.J.J. Se to Doolittle, Dec. 12, 1897.
    - Opinion given on marginal notes on A.P.S. copy of Declaration of Independence, [1897]; 11x8-1/2; Dreer, Ferdinand J. (Ferdinand Julius), 1812-1902
      A.D.S. 1p., end.: 1897 "The interlineations on this draft are in my opinion in the hand writing of Thomas Jefferson."